# Hanif Uddin Mobile: 07368446235

Email: <a href="mailto:hanif.uddz@gmail.com">hanif.uddz@gmail.com</a> LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:hanif-uddin">hinkedIn.com/in/hanif-uddin</a>

A competent engineer and self-motivated web developer that works diligently to achieve his goals. A persevering individual with an ability to solve problems with various technologies. Developed a disciplined work ethic through work experience with team working and critical skills that are essential in the engineering industry. Dedicated to continuously learning new technologies and improving upon skill sets in front-end development.

### Education

### freeCodeCamp | Responsive Web Design Certification

**July 2023 – September 2023** 

Immersive web development bootcamp representing 300 hours of instruction and self-taught coding. The course involved learning the fundamental languages of webpages including HTML and CSS. The major tasks involved building webpages via numerous projects, with a focus on responsive design.

## **University of Lancaster | Mechanical Engineering BEng Hons**

October 2020 - June 2023

Grade: First

<u>Relevant Modules:</u> Engineering Management, Vibration Analysis and Applications, Design and Manufacturing, Engineering Materials, Machine Elements, Energy Conversion, Engineering Analysis, Instrumentation and Control, Power Engineering, Engineering Projects, Business Development Project, Engineering Mechanics, Fluid Mechanics & Thermodynamics, Materials and Design, Programming Fundamentals

#### Sir Joseph Williamson's Mathematical School, Rochester | A-Levels

**September 2018 – July 2020** 

Mathematics - A; Physics - B; Design & Technology - C

Sir Joseph Williamson's Mathematical School, Rochester | GCSEs

**September 2013 – July 2018** 

11 GCSE or Equivalent – Grades 9 - 6 including Maths - 9, English - 6 and Sciences – 8 to 9

## Technical Skills

- Proficiency in front-end web development HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- ➤ IT Proficiency in Microsoft Office Produced professional reports, analysed and presented data accurately in Word, PowerPoint and Excel.
- ➤ Programming experience in C/C++ via Microsoft Visual Studio IDE as well as being implemented through programming embedded systems for various university projects.
- Experience in using SolidWorks Developing 3D CAD models and technical drawings.
- Proficiency in MBSE tools including MATLAB and Simulink Modelling vehicle/control systems, simulating and analysing electronic circuits.
- > Practise with Ansys CFD analysis, stress analysis of a hollow tube using FEM.

# **Project Experience**

## **Lancaster University | Student**

October 2020 - June 2023

Role: Completed projects throughout university that have provided the knowledge and skills that are applicable within the engineering industry.

Final Year Individual BEng Project (First-Class): Successfully designed a traction control system for application in Lancaster University's Formula Student vehicle. Using MATLAB and Simulink, I created a virtual model of the vehicle and tested against the system requirements via simulations. This was efficiently done by taking an analytical approach with the tasks and communicating effectively with the formula student team on developing and tuning the system to their specifications.

- Robot Project: Was dedicated as the sole programmer and leader of the electronics team in a group to build an autonomous robot which followed a line and placed an envelope on a raised shelf. With C programming on an embedded system, an electronic circuit was built alongside to power the motors and produce a line following sensor, along with a built chassis to house the components. Through concise planning and direction, the tasks were completed successfully.
- ➤ <u>IMechE Repeatable Vehicle Challenge:</u> Worked in a team to design a self-moving vehicle that interacts with a wall and returns to its starting position. I worked in cooperation with other members to design a CAD model, poster, and video presentation. Was applauded by the lecturer for a feasible and creative design to the extent of achieving 2<sup>nd</sup> place at the national competition.
- <u>Business Development Project:</u> Worked in a group of diverse disciplines and backgrounds to create an original business idea which ultimately resulted in selling an organisational and washable laundry basket. As head of marketing, I was required to produce creative methods to promote the product via a client-focused approach. I worked with other members to come up with innovative ideas and concepts, having ultimately produced a formidable report and presentation that represents a successful product in terms of quality and customer satisfaction.

# **Employment and Work Experience**

### **Lancaster University | Engineering Ambassador**

December 2022 – September 2023

Role: Promoting the School of Engineering to prospective students and applicants via delivering and supporting various engaging events and addressing queries proficiently.

- Adaptable: Seamlessly transitioning between different responsibilities when required by the organiser.
- > Time Management: Managing and supporting the delivery of tours and activities of the School.
- > Teamwork: Communicated and collaborated with fellow colleagues when setting up events.
- Working under Pressure: Maintained composure and ensured seamless experience for guests during fast-paced events.
- > Leadership: Delegated tasks to fellow team members and coordinated open day activities.

## **Argos | Warehouse Operative**

August 2022 - September 2022

Role: Picking, packing, sorting, and loading orders for delivery in a fast-paced work environment.

- Organisation: Picked items were processed and placed in the correct area, kept the sortation area clear and clean.
- Communication: Shared operational updates of the facilities and allocated different tasks with other members to meet quotas efficiently.
- > Reliable: Responsible for training new employees to perform the duties successfully.
- Self-motivated: Built and maintained a can-do approach during operational setbacks, being self-incentivised to take up extra duties.

### **Awards and Achievements**

#### iMechE Design Challenge | National Finalist

**April 2021** 

- Designed a repeatable self-moving vehicle which reached the national finals. It aided in the progression of my ability to tackle complicated situations independently and within a team.
- > IT Competency: Utilising IT knowledge to produce a video presentation and poster for the competition via Microsoft office applications and video editing software.

#### **DofE Award | Bronze and Silver**

**September 2015 – June 2017** 

Earning the bronze and silver award showed my perseverance and determination in accomplishing all my objectives.